Jeonggyu Lee

WE'RE HIRING! Software Engineer 2 at Microsoft

Summary

I am a well-rounded Software Engineer with 5+ years of experience from startup to Fortune 50. Specifically I have experience working in Open-Source, Video Gaming, Commercial Scientific Software, Internal Research Tools and Web Development.

In my spare time I enjoy developing my hobby projects and contributing to open source projects. Some are available at:

- http://github.com/whyi
- http://www.whyi.net/

Experience

Software Engineer 2 at Microsoft

April 2015 - Present

WE ARE HIRING!!!

The Microsoft Cloud Infrastructure and Operations (MCIO) group is an exciting and fast evolving engineering group within Microsoft. MCIO's mission is to optimize and deliver industry leading cloud infrastructure and foundational technologies for Microsoft's online services. The organization is responsible for strategy and delivery of the foundational platform for all Microsoft Online Services including demand and capacity forecasting, supply chain, data centers, networking, bandwidth, operations, and incident management. MCIO supports over 200 online businesses including Bing, O365, OneDrive, Xbox and Windows Azure branded services.

https://careers.microsoft.com/search.aspx?
pg=0#&&p2=all&p1=all&p3=all&p4=all&p0=XMCIOERX&p5=all

Founder at http://www.whyi.net/

May 2002 - Present

- Developing and maintaining my personal website http://www.WhyI.Net/ since 2002.
- Open source Art Gallery Single Page App @ http://www.whyi.net/hyunju
- Check out the project section below for more details.

Senior Software Developer at Aequitas Capital Management

April 2014 - March 2015 (1 year)

- Worked on the Unigo (formerly EducationPlus/+U) venture.
- Integration with affiliated (partner) websites by utilizing server-to-server communication.
- Revamped the legacy website into new Unigo.com RESTful API to reuse the existing feature.
- Enhanced internal Database Migration process with Ruby script.
- Automated front-end unit-testing by setting up Jenkins CI from scratch.
- Technologies: C# ASP.NET MVC5, Grails, Angular.Js, MSSQL, Dependency Injection, Continuous Integration, Rest API, Bootstrap for responsiveness.

Software Development Engineer II at Groupon

September 2013 - April 2014 (8 months)

- Groupon Getaways Team
- Implemented backend services of merchant facing travel application.
- Technologies: Java, Linux, MySQL, Redis, HBase, data grid, cloud computing, Rest API.

Software Engineer at Intel

July 2010 - August 2013 (3 years 2 months)

- Software Engineer for Core CAD Technologies, Design and Technology Solutions (DTS) Division.
- Maintained internal semiconductor device modeling software to help scientists modeling the next generation transistor.

Software Developer at Wolfram Research

January 2010 - June 2010 (6 months)

- Improved Import and Export of 3D Graphics File Formats in Mathematica 8.
- Designed and implemented import/export capability of VTK(Visualization Toolkit) file format.

Senior Software Developer at AccelerEyes

August 2009 - December 2009 (5 months)

• Worked on vector field rendering using GPU.

Engineering Intern at Kaneva

January 2009 - May 2009 (5 months)

• Designed and Implemented Kaneva Instant Messenger.

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology

Master of Science, Computer Science, 2007 - 2009

Activities and Societies: Co-op program

Jeonggyu Lee

WE'RE HIRING! Software Engineer 2 at Microsoft



Contact Jeonggyu on LinkedIn